Yeah, I just want to start off uh you
know, I think some thank yous are in
line. First off, thank you to uh Mr.
Rooney, Mr. Khan, and uh Coach McCarthy
for, you know, giving me this
opportunity and and taking a chance on
me. Um and then you I'm thankful for the
the coaches back at Navy that have
helped get me to this spot. Um Coach
Newberry, uh Coach Yokitis, Coach Cole,
Coach Kronic. Um and then my family, you
know, they they have a big role in why
I'm here. Um, so I'm I'm super thankful
for my family as well.
>> Eli, the Steelers are very touched by
that moment there at the end when you
were introduced. What was that like for
you to walk up through that door?
>> Yeah, it was um it was it was pretty
incredible. I think you know the biggest
thing is is for me I turn that corner
and you see the city skyline in the
background and then the the crowd is
like 90% black and gold. It's all
Steelers fans out there and um you know
it just it was such a cool moment.
Everything kind of just came together
and you know I was pretty overwhelmed
with the emotions but you know I'm just
thankful that I had this opportunity
that the NFL invited me to be in the
green room and um it just you know
allowed for this moment to to be even
more special.
>> Eli, as the draft was approaching, did
you allow yourself the thought of maybe
the Steelers are going to take me? So,
you know, um I think leading up to the
draft, there's always some buzz going
around, especially from your agent. He's
hearing things from different teams. Um
you know, but I I think that buzz was
probably the loudest from the Steelers.
Uh so I definitely had some sort of
inkling coming into uh the draft that
the Steelers were interested and I would
potentially be drafted by them. Um you
know, but you know, time was kind of
ticking down at the end and I saw they
had one more one more pick. So, you
know, I was I was hoping like back of my
mind I was like, "Come on." and then the
the the call came through and um it was
it was pretty cool. So,
>> and I know it only happened an hour ago,
but has it sunk in yet?
>> You know, I don't I don't think fully. I
think it's going to take a little bit of
time probably to sleep on it and wake up
tomorrow morning. Like I'm a Pittsburgh
Steeler now. Um I think it, you know,
hasn't fully set in.
>> Hey, what what can you do for the
Steelers as a player?
>> Yeah, so you know, I think the biggest
thing about me is you're getting a
football player. Um, you know, on
offense, I can do a lot of different a
lot of different things. That's
something I've been doing for almost
eight years now, high school and
college. Uh, playing a few different
positions at a high level. So, on the
offense side of things, you you're
getting some versatility. And then on
special teams, I played all four phases
um in in college, so I'm able to
contribute there and and make a
difference. But I think the biggest
thing is you look at the Steelers
organization um and the mentality that,
you know, this this team's been built
off. Um, you know, I think I bring that
same thing that that toughness, that
grittiness that, you know, that not only
the the Steelers, but the the city of
Pittsburgh has always been about.
>> Eli, when you saw the Steelers call you,
the 412 number pop up, did you know in
that moment that it was the Steelers, or
did you think maybe this is like a
friend whose number I forgot to say in
my phone, something like that?
>> Yeah, I had I had um my first thought
was definitely Steelers. I saw they were
on the clock and I was like, they're
like it was just it all kind of hit me
at once. Um, yeah, but I thought it was
them. Eli, do you remember the the first
moment when you dreamed as a kid maybe
of playing for the Pittsburgh Steelers?
And what was the key to making that
dream a reality?
>> Yeah, I think the the earliest moment
for me that that I can remember is
watching the Steelers play the Cardinals
in the Super Bowl. Um, and just, you
know, watching that game and everything
that took place for, you know, us to go
out and and win that Super Bowl. I think
that was really when it started. Um, you
know, I remember James Harrison that
play specifically, his 100 yard pick six
and, um, you know, I went asked my dad
shortly after that for James Harrison
jersey, which I got later on that
summer. But, so I think then is really
when it started.
>> What are you looking forward to about
being back uh, every day? Obviously, I
haven't been too far away, but being
back where you're from, what will that
be like?
>> Yeah, you know, I think the biggest
thing that I'm looking forward to um, is
really just devoting 100% of my time to
football. You know, the last four years
I've kind of had this, you know,
juggling match of just military and
academics and football and just trying
to find time for everything. And this is
the first time that I'll really have,
you know, all of my time to to dedicate
to football and I'm excited for that.
>> Pittsburgh, as a Pittsburgh guy, what
was it like seeing the city kind of
transformed by the draft? I mean, could
you in all your dreams, could you have
imagined seeing the draft stage in front
of Back Rusher Stadium and you walking
across it? Yeah,
I was. It was pretty cool seeing it all
take place. Um I'm glad that this city
got the publicity for the draft. I think
people are finally starting to realize
like this city rocks like and more
people need to realize that that uh you
know what goes down here. Um but just
kind of how everything was set up. I
think it was just such a fantastic event
across the board and I think everything
went right. Um and you know for me to be
able to go out there and kind of
contribute to that and be a part of this
event um was really special.
>> Go from a zero star recruit
>> to now an NFL football player. What were
some of the most important things within
your journey that that allowed you to
achieve this?
>> Yep.
>> You know, I think you know, like you
said, not being super highly recruited.
Um, for me it was kind of frustrating
initially. Uh, you're like wondering why
why am I not getting stars or offers,
whatever it may be. But, you know,
something my dad really helped me kind
of understand is that, you know, use
this as a a fuel, a way to motivate you.
And I think that taught me how to work.
It taught me how to, you know, make
myself better on my own accord. Um, so I
I think that's the the biggest lesson
that I kind of took away from that time
is, um, you know, just use it as
motivation and, uh, become a better
football player as a result.
>> Eli, what are your duties now after
going to Navy? Now, what does that look
like moving forward here?
>> Yep. So, uh, May 22nd is my graduation
and I'll commission into the reserves in
the United States Marine Corps. Um, and
all of my, uh, you know, time and focus
will be on football. I won't have any
military obligations taking me away from
football. Um they may ask me to do some
sort of like PR related event in the
offseason to shine light on the Marine
Corps or the the military, but that's um
kind of all all I have to do. Um and
then afterwards, I'll have the choice to
go back and serve in an active role. But
um as uh as as far as I'm concerned
right now, you know, I'm worried about
being a Steeler.
>> Eli, is there a Steeler or non-Steeler
past or present that you modeled your
game after?
Um, you know, I've I've always looked up
to Chris McCaffrey, I think he's a just
a fantastic player and plays the game
the right way. And, you know, as a as
watching him and and the way, especially
in the past game, the way he's able to
get open and and make things happen in
space, uh, is something that I've
always, you know, tried to study and and
replicate.
>> What was your journey at the Naval
Academy like?
>> Um, man, it was tough some days and I
mean that that's done on purpose. You
know, it's um it's designed to be
stressful. They want you to have to
operate in a stressful environment and
get used to that. Um, but you know, I'm
thankful for those those tough times.
You know, there there were some long
nights there and you got a lot on your
plate. Um, but it it just teaches you
how to, you know, deal with that stress
and uh to really time management, be
able to plan out your your days and
weeks in a time that makes sense for
you. Um, but yeah, the the the academy
is tough sometimes, but I'm glad I went
through that struggle. I think it made
me a better person. Was that preparing
you for days like today or do you still
get nervous as you're waiting to hear
your name go?
>> I was definitely definitely nervous. My
heart was, you know, my heart rate is
probably a little elevated today. I
would say more so than usual, but um
sitting on sitting on a couch isn't too
bad compared to what we got to do on a
day-to-day basis there. So,
>> you mentioned want to get a James
Harrison jersey. He was around this
weekend. Did you get to talk to him, see
him, anything like that?
>> I did not have the chance, but um I
would love to sometime. It' be pretty
cool. Do
>> you still have that jersey? I'd have to
check. I I would assume so. I I did not
get rid of it. It'd be something like my
my parents would be like, he doesn't it
doesn't fit him anymore. But yeah, you
know, kind of reflecting back on your
2021 state title run with Mount Lemon.
Um how did that kind of grow your
football career and and what did that
teach you, especially to do it alongside
a guy like Alex Tesco who then became
obviously your teammate?
>> Yeah, it's funny you ask. Um you know,
you look at that Mount Lebanon team. Um
we're just we're a normal public school.
there's no recruiting going on. I've
been playing that senior class I played
with that year. I've been playing with
literally my entire life since like
first grade. Um and we we played
football throughout, you know, growing
up and then that senior year we just
happened to be really good. And I think
that was the result of us playing so
long together and getting to know each
other and, you know, kind of having this
love for each other, this like brotherly
love. Um, you know, I think that really
taught me that, you know, an important
part of any football team is that, you
know, connection you have to your
teammates and making sure that you're
looking out for them. And the same thing
goes at Navy. There's no NIL or anything
like that. It's just, you know, you're
you're worried about your your brothers
to the left and right of you. So, that's
something I took away from that.
>> Did you go to games growing up or did
you ever go to a training camp or
anything like that
>> for the Steelers? Yeah, I went to a
bunch. the mo I was at the game that we
beat the Ravens and they missed the
field goal like in December. So that was
the most recent game. I went to the
playoff game last year in Baltimore.
Definitely got chirped a little bit. I
was full Steelered up. Um but uh yeah,
I've been to a ton, you know, growing up
and then even recently
>> wear jerseys now still like
>> if I'm going to a game I will. But um
>> players in your collection or
>> so I snatched my dad's old Paul Malo
jersey and I have my dad had an old Rod
Woodson jersey too that I'll throw on
here here and there. So
>> you know just for clarification you talk
about going in and being a reserveist
while you are like do you have any kind
of obligations in terms of like an
annual training or anything like that?
>> Sorry. Can you repeat that?
>> Like as a reserveist will you have any
obligations with like annual training or
anything like that? As far as I'm
concerned, no. Uh I've been talking with
Rayon Lane. He's a safety in uh
Jacksonville who got drafted out of Navy
last year and um you know, he he hasn't
had to deal with any of that. The only
thing he'll have to do, like I said, was
that PR kind of a few things in the
offseason, but nothing significant.
Nothing in season.
>> Eli, how does your military physical
training prepare you for football
training?
>> Yeah. Um, you know, I think the biggest
thing, uh, you train for in the military
is just, you know, conditioning. Um,
being able to operate at a real long
time. And, um, that's something that we
definitely do in the the academy
offense. We try to wear you down
throughout the game. Um, so I'd say, you
know, that that conditioning is
something that I've worked on throughout
my career and something that I do well.
>> How are you going to spend the rest of
tonight and what does, uh, the next
couple weeks look like for you until
rookie mini camp?
>> Yeah, so I live about 15 20 minutes from
here. Um, I have a bunch of family and
friends at my house and then like 20 of
my Naval Academy football teammates
drove up for the weekend. So, we had a
little convoy coming in after class
Friday. Um, but they're all they're all
waiting back at the uh at the house and
you know, I'm I'm going to go hang out
with them.
>> Two more questions.
>> Is that 71?
>> It is. Yep.
>> What's it been like being around Ravens
fans for the past 3, four years?
>> It's uh it's it's pretty rough
sometimes. There's there's a lot at the
academy, too, since it's in Maryland.
It's pretty close proximity to uh to
Baltimore, so you're definitely around
them. Um but yeah, it's uh you just have
to, you know, close your ears sometimes.
>> Thank you, Eli. Thanks for your service.
>> Thank you guys.